Find your place in the universe.
Treasure Planet is a science fiction, adventure,
animation film directed by Ron Clements.
When space galleon cabin boy Jim Hawkins discovers a map to an intergalactic "loot of a thousand worlds," a cyborg cook
named John Silver teaches him to battle supernovas and space storms on their journey to find treasure.
Jim Hawkins (voice), played by Joseph Gordon-Levitt.
John Silver (voice), played by Brian Murray.
Captain Amelia (voice), played by Emma Thompson.
Doctor Doppler (voice), played by David Hyde Pierce.
B.E.N. (voice), played by Martin Short.
Morph (voice), played by Dane A. Davis.
Treasure Planet is a 2002 American animated science fiction adventure film directed by John
Musker and Ron Clements and written by Musker, Clements and Rob Edwards.
Produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation, it is a science fiction adaptation of Robert Louis Stevenson's novel Treasure Island
(1883) and the third Disney adaptation of the novel, following Treasure Island (1950) and Muppet Treasure Island (1996).
In the film's setting, spaceships are powered by solar sails and resemble the
18th-century sailing vessels of the original Treasure Island.
The film features the voices of Joseph Gordon-Levitt, Brian Murray, David Hyde Pierce, Martin Short,  Roscoe Lee
Browne, Emma Thompson, Michael Wincott, Laurie Metcalf, and Patrick McGoohan in his final role.
The musical score was composed by James Newton Howard, with
songs written and performed by John Rzeznik.
Clements and Musker pitched the concept for the film during
production of The Little Mermaid (1989).
Development began after they finished their work on Hercules (1997).
It employs a novel technique of hand-drawn 2D traditional
animation set atop 3D computer animation.
With a budget of $140 million, it is the most expensive
traditionally animated film to date.
Treasure Planet premiered in Paris on November 6, 2002, and was released in
the United States on November 27 by Walt Disney Pictures.
It was the first film to be released
simultaneously in regular and IMAX theaters.
The film was a box-office failure, earning $109 million
worldwide against a budget of $140 million.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and was nominated
for Best Animated Feature at the 75th Academy Awards.
The film has since gained a cult following.
The film explores themes of mutiny, space marine,
based on novel or book, cyborg, map.
The tone is thought_provoking.